Cole, Paul Collection of New York State Council on Vocational Education (NYS COVE) Papers 6267
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Paul Cole Collection of New York State Council on Vocational Education (NYS COVE) Papers
1984-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Cole, Paul
6267
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Papers.
8259724
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 24, 2008
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 11, 2016
Biographical / Historical
David Lawrence Cole was a graduate of Harvard University (BS., 1921) and Fairleigh Dickinson University (LL.B., 1924, LL.D., 1964.) Although he practiced law in Paterson, N.J. from 1926 until his death as senior partner in the law firm of Cole, Berman & Belksy, David Cole will chiefly be remembered for a distinguished career as a government arbitrator and mediator. In this field he served on numerous state and federal boards and in various governmental agencies. Cole was chairman of the New Jersey State Board of Mediation; a public member of Region 2, United States War Labor Board; and chairman of the Presidential Boards of Inquiry in the bituminous coal industry (1948) and in the longshore industry (1953, 1968). Cole was also a member or chairman of numerous Presidential Emergency Boards which settled disputes in the railroad and airline industries (1948-1958); the chairman of the conciliation service for the New York City transit service (1961-1965); director of the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (1952-1953); chairman of the New Jersey Governor's Committee on Public Utility Strike Service (1952-1953); member of the President's Labor-Management Advisory Committee (1961-1964); and member of the New York Governor's Public Employee Relations Committee (1966-1968), which established the New York State Public Employee Relations Board. Cole was also appointed as chairman of the President's Commission on Industrial Peace in 1973.
Beyond his public service, Mr. Cole was active as a counsel for employer groups in the textile industry (1926-1942) and as an impartial chairman for other labor-management contract disputes. He was also impartial arbitrator for the AFL-CIO Internal Disputes Plan (1954-1976), served as a visiting professor at the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University (1954-1955) and was Kestenbaum lecturer at Harvard in 1962. Mr. Cole was the author of INDUSTRIAL PEACE (1963).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6202 P(d): New York State AFL-CIO Paul Cole Digital Photographs 6202: New York State AFL-CIO Paul Cole Files 6202 OH: New York State AFL-CIO Paul Cole Interviews Oral History on Minidiscs 6202 AV: New York State AFL-CIO Paul Cole Interviews Audio-Visual Materials
Cole, Paul; New York State Council on Vocational Education
8259724
- Murry Begtraum High School, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Where Others Leave Off - Intermediate Distrct 287, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Hennepin Technical Centers
- Dakota County Area Vocational Technical Institue (folder 1 of 4), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Dakota County Area Vocational Technical Institue (folder 2 of 4), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Dakota County Area Vocational Technical Institue (folder 3 of 4), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Dakota County Area Vocational Technical Institue (folder 4 of 4) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Phone Bank Budget, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  New York State AFL-CIO Council on Political Education
- Letters and Communications Regarding Mondale Campaign, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Briefing Book, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Notebook, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Meeting Minutes, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Jan. 10th. New York State Council on Vocational Education (NYS Cove)
- The Citizen Bee Guide to American Studies, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Conference Materials, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Oct. 29-30th. Local Council on Vocational Education in New York State
- New York State United Teachers (folder 1 of 2), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- New York State United Teachers (folder 2 f 2), 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Leadership '84, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Apr. 28th. New York State Young Democrats
- Technical Committee Meeting, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Decemberr 28, 1988. New York State Council on Vocational Education (NYS Cove)
- Cornell University, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Council Meeting Materials, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  October 21, 1987. New York State Council on Vocational Education (NYS Cove)
- Council Meeting Materials, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  April 18, 1988. New York State Council on Vocational Education (NYS Cove)
- New York State Council on Vocational Education (NYS Cove), 1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Council Meeting Materials, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  September 8, 1988. New York State Council on Vocational Education (NYS Cove)
- Council Meeting Materials, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  January 19, 1988. New York State Council on Vocational Education (NYS Cove)
- Education and Industry Alliance, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 14)